[
  {
    "question": "Despite the smile that spread from ear to ear, her eyes relayed a certain _____.",
    "correct_answer": "sorrow",
    "distractor": [
      "jubilance",
      "mischievousness",
      "vision",
      "liveliness"
    ],
    "support": "Sorrow: feel grief\nJubilance: a feeling of extreme joy\nMischievousness: an attribute of mischievous children\nVision: a vivid mental image\nLiveliness: general activity and motion",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/0/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some historians see the Jacksonians as little more than ruthless capitalists who had _____ regard for individual welfare.",
    "correct_answer": "scant",
    "distractor": [
      "mixed",
      "undue",
      "inconsistent",
      "obtrusive"
    ],
    "support": "Scant: less than the correct or legal or full amount often deliberately so\nMixed: consisting of a haphazard assortment of different kinds\nUndue: not yet payable\nInconsistent: displaying a lack of consistency\nObtrusive: sticking out; protruding",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/5ekxgk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of social science`s major themes is that of stability versus change; to what extent are individual personalities _____ yet different over time?",
    "correct_answer": "static",
    "distractor": [
      "transient",
      "maladjusted",
      "disturbed",
      "discreet"
    ],
    "support": "Static: not in physical motion\nTransient: of a mental act; causing effects outside the mind\nMaladjusted: poorly adjusted to demands and stresses of daily living\nDisturbed: having the place or position changed\nDiscreet: marked by prudence or modesty and wise self-restraint",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/a9kxhk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Erie Canal`s completion caused _____ economic ripples; property values and industrial output along its route rose exponentially.",
    "correct_answer": "prodigious",
    "distractor": [
      "persist cut",
      "invaluable",
      "incredulous",
      "severe"
    ],
    "support": "Prodigious: so great in size or force or extent as to elicit awe\nInvaluable: having incalculable monetary, intellectual, or spiritual worth\nIncredulous: not disposed or willing to believe; unbelieving\nSevere: intensely or extremely bad or unpleasant in degree or quality",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/55kxik/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Voters have become so inured to the fickle nature of politicians that they responded to the levy of a new tax with _____.",
    "correct_answer": "stolidity",
    "distractor": [
      "amazement",
      "exasperation",
      "alarm",
      "perplexity"
    ],
    "support": "Stolidity: apathy demonstrated by an absence of emotional reactions\nAmazement: the feeling that accompanies something extremely surprising\nExasperation: an exasperated feeling of annoyance\nAlarm: fill with apprehension or alarm; cause to be unpleasantly surprised\nPerplexity: trouble or confusion resulting from complexity",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/48kxjk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "The division between child-rearing goals that emphasize originality and personalization and those that place emphasis on adoption of conventions and compliance with rules discloses a _____that stems from the principles on which these goals are based.",
    "correct_answer": "contradiction",
    "distractor": [
      "monotony",
      "benefit",
      "forseeability",
      "genius"
    ],
    "support": "Contradiction: opposition between two conflicting forces or ideas\nMonotony: the quality of wearisome constancy, routine, and lack of variety\nBenefit: derive a benefit from\nGenius: someone who has exceptional intellectual ability and originality",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/d0kxkk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Despite her mentor`s advice that she attempt to sound consistently _____, the graduate student often resorted to using slang when presenting significant parts of her thesis, her habitual speech patterns overriding her years of learning.",
    "correct_answer": "erudite",
    "distractor": [
      "lucid",
      "didactic",
      "panegyrical",
      "rational"
    ],
    "support": "Erudite: having or showing profound knowledge\nLucid: (of language\nDidactic: instructive (especially excessively\nPanegyrical: formally expressing praise\nRational: consistent with or based on or using reason",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/9fl06k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Western culture has so influenced Middle Eastern music that even the latter`s roles of composer and performer, at one time inseparable, have now begun to _____.",
    "correct_answer": "diverge",
    "distractor": [
      "divulge",
      "retreat",
      "retrench",
      "fuse"
    ],
    "support": "Diverge: move or draw apart\nDivulge: make known to the public information that was previously known only to a few people or that was meant to be kept a secret\nRetreat: pull back or move away or backward\nRetrench: tighten one's belt; use resources carefully\nFuse: mix together different elements",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/cfl0xk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although tranquilizers usually have a _____effect, this is not always the case, especially when the abuse of these drugs results in a failure to induce the much-desired sleep.",
    "correct_answer": "soporific",
    "distractor": [
      "sedulous",
      "coruscating",
      "debilitating",
      "pond rat ing"
    ],
    "support": "Soporific: sleep inducing\nSedulous: marked by care and persistent effort\nCoruscating: reflect brightly\nDebilitating: impairing the strength and vitality",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/46l0zk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Science and religion each have core tenets that are considered _____; however, because some scientific tenets are in conflict with some religious ones, these tenets cannot all be correct.",
    "correct_answer": "axiomatic",
    "distractor": [
      "historic",
      "disputable",
      "ubiquitous",
      "empirical"
    ],
    "support": "Axiomatic: evident without proof or argument\nHistoric: belonging to the past; of what is important or famous in the past\nDisputable: capable of being disproved\nUbiquitous: being present everywhere at once\nEmpirical: derived from experiment and observation rather than theory",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/dfl19k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Oscar Wilde`s The Importance of Being Earnest satirizes the _____nature of upper crust British society; its characters take trivial concerns seriously while glibly dismissing important ones.",
    "correct_answer": "shallow",
    "distractor": [
      "maladaptive",
      "insincere",
      "unusual",
      "insignificant"
    ],
    "support": "Shallow: lacking physical depth; having little spatial extension downward or inward from an outer surface or backward or outward from a center\nMaladaptive: showing faulty adaptation\nInsincere: lacking sincerity\nUnusual: not usual or common or ordinary\nInsignificant: signifying nothing",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/77l1ck/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Despite what _____philosophies of child-rearing suggest, there is no imperative that the day-to-day action of raising a child be simple, unambiguous and unchanging-no requirement, in other words, ensures that life follow philosophy.",
    "correct_answer": "systematic",
    "distractor": [
      "inexact",
      "aggressive",
      "random",
      "shameless"
    ],
    "support": "Systematic: characterized by order and planning\nInexact: not exact\nAggressive: having or showing determination and energetic pursuit of your ends\nRandom: lacking any definite plan or order or purpose; governed by or depending on chance\nShameless: feeling no shame",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/bdl1zk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Having squandered his life`s savings on unprofitable business ventures, the _____entrepreneur was forced to live in squalor.",
    "correct_answer": "insolvent",
    "distractor": [
      "former",
      "unlikely",
      "perturbed",
      "eccentric"
    ],
    "support": "Insolvent: unable to meet or discharge financial obligations\nFormer: referring to the first of two things or persons mentioned (or the earlier one or ones of several\nUnlikely: not likely to be true or to occur or to have occurred\nPerturbed: thrown into a state of agitated confusion; (`rattled' is an informal term\nEccentric: conspicuously or grossly unconventional or unusual",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/553/152736570620606599/8bl23k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Video game enthusiasts know that, while the astounding advances in technological innovation might increase the level of fun of the gaming experience, such a result is by no means _____.",
    "correct_answer": "ineluctable",
    "distractor": [
      "desultory",
      "endemic",
      "salient",
      "seminal"
    ],
    "support": "Ineluctable: impossible to avoid or evade\nDesultory: marked by lack of definite plan or regularity or purpose; jumping from one thing to another\nEndemic: of or relating to a disease (or anything resembling a disease\nSalient: having a quality that thrusts itself into attention\nSeminal: pertaining to or containing or consisting of semen",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/0/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dismissed by the establishment, professing nothing but disdain for the canon, and yet beloved by his followers who trumpet his _____ opinions, the raffish pundit is laughing all the way to the bank.",
    "correct_answer": "iconoclastic",
    "distractor": [
      "blithe",
      "inveterate",
      "meretricious",
      "meritless"
    ],
    "support": "Iconoclastic: characterized by attack on established beliefs or institutions\nBlithe: lacking or showing a lack of due concern\nInveterate: habitual\nMeretricious: like or relating to a prostitute\nMeritless: without merit; of little or no value or use",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/3ck3ik/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although his latest project was relatively _____-little more than a few basic plot points scribbled on a napkin-the veteran screenwriter easily sold the story to a major Hollywood studio.",
    "correct_answer": "undeveloped",
    "distractor": [
      "polished",
      "convoluted",
      "prosaic",
      "tortuous"
    ],
    "support": "Undeveloped: not developed, mature, or fully formulated\nPolished: perfected or made shiny and smooth\nConvoluted: rolled longitudinally upon itself\nProsaic: not fanciful or imaginative\nTortuous: highly complex or intricate and occasionally devious",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/3bk3mk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Despite being located in hot and sunny California, San Francisco is famous for its _____ weather, engendered by the confluence of two different meteorological systems in the Bay Area.",
    "correct_answer": "adverse",
    "distractor": [
      "stimulating",
      "balmy",
      "appealing",
      "duplicitous"
    ],
    "support": "Adverse: contrary to your interests or welfare\nStimulating: rousing or quickening activity or the senses\nBalmy: informal or slang terms for mentally irregular\nAppealing: able to attract interest or draw favorable attention\nDuplicitous: marked by deliberate deceptiveness especially by pretending one set of feelings and acting under the influence of another",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/e4k3nk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Possessing few natural resources upon its newly-granted independence in 1863, Singapore remained economically _____ until an influx of industrialization and foreign investment took hold there.",
    "correct_answer": "dubious",
    "distractor": [
      "powerful",
      "prosperous",
      "solvent",
      "fortuitous"
    ],
    "support": "Dubious: fraught with uncertainty or doubt\nPowerful: having great power or force or potency or effect\nProsperous: in fortunate circumstances financially; moderately rich\nSolvent: capable of meeting financial obligations\nFortuitous: having no cause or apparent cause",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/31k3ok/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Even though legislators claimed the Contagious Diseases Acts strengthened the nation, social purists argued the Acts _____ the nation's moral growth by encouraging licentious behavior.",
    "correct_answer": "hampered",
    "distractor": [
      "advanced",
      "ameliorated",
      "supplanted",
      "enhanced"
    ],
    "support": "Hampered: prevent the progress or free movement of\nAdvanced: farther along in physical or mental development\nAmeliorated: to make better\nSupplanted: take the place or move into the position of\nEnhanced: increased or intensified in value or beauty or quality",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/f2k3qk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "The new lecture hall's _____ design reflected the architect`s minimalist influences.",
    "correct_answer": "unadorned",
    "distractor": [
      "posh",
      "intricate",
      "refulgent",
      "grandiose"
    ],
    "support": "Unadorned: not decorated with something to increase its beauty or distinction\nPosh: elegant and fashionable\nIntricate: having many complexly arranged elements; elaborate\nRefulgent: radiating or as if radiating light\nGrandiose: impressive because of unnecessary largeness or grandeur; used to show disapproval",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/91k3rk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Modern tennis fans have come to realize that, although, quantum technological leaps in racquet technology have lead to _____ increases in the speed and power with which players can hit the ball, this has not necessarily lead to a more entertaining game.",
    "correct_answer": "commensurate",
    "distractor": [
      "innocuous",
      "halcyon",
      "malleable",
      "tractable"
    ],
    "support": "Commensurate: corresponding in size or degree or extent\nInnocuous: not injurious to physical or mental health\nHalcyon: idyllically calm and peaceful; suggesting happy tranquillity\nMalleable: easily influenced\nTractable: easily managed (controlled or taught or molded",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/9fk3uk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Many Major League Baseball relief pitchers choose an electrifying theme song to play as they take the mound; the song _____ their fans and instills fear in their opponents.",
    "correct_answer": "innervates",
    "distractor": [
      "eviscerates",
      "enervates",
      "assuages",
      "pervades"
    ],
    "support": "Innervates: supply nerves to (some organ or body part\nEviscerates: surgically remove a part of a structure or an organ\nEnervates: weaken mentally or morally\nAssuages: cause to be more favorably inclined; gain the good will of\nPervades: spread or diffuse through",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/8ak3vk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Emmet Ray, a fictional jazz guitarist in Woody Allen's film Sweet and Lowdown, is a paradoxical character; while he displays sophisticated musical artistry, his personality is typically _____ .",
    "correct_answer": "maladroit",
    "distractor": [
      "petulant",
      "elegant",
      "audacious",
      "multi-faceted"
    ],
    "support": "Maladroit: not adroit\nPetulant: easily irritated or annoyed\nElegant: refined and tasteful in appearance or behavior or style\nAudacious: invulnerable to fear or intimidation",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/44/152736637597563714/6fk3wk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Susan _____ the theater; she bought tickets for all the shows put on by the local drama group.",
    "correct_answer": "cherished",
    "distractor": [
      "abhorred",
      "owned",
      "loathed",
      "managed"
    ],
    "support": "Cherished: characterized by feeling or showing fond affection for\nAbhorred: find repugnant\nOwned: having an owner; often used in combination\nLoathed: find repugnant\nManaged: be successful; achieve a goal",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/0/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Currently _____ in philately, Roger decided to pursue his new hobby because he had already become an expert numismatist.",
    "correct_answer": "a dilettante",
    "distractor": [
      "a philanderer",
      "a mentor",
      "a specialist",
      "an eccentric"
    ],
    "support": "Cherished: characterized by feeling or showing fond affection for\nAbhorred: find repugnant\nOwned: having an owner; often used in combination\nLoathed: find repugnant\nManaged: be successful; achieve a goal",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/92k2fk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Prior to taking on the new invader, the defending army had engaged in arduous combat; it is likely that the _____ resulting from waging two battles in two days played a part in its subsequent defeat.",
    "correct_answer": "enervation",
    "distractor": [
      "bellicosity",
      "pugnacity",
      "pacification",
      "aggravation"
    ],
    "support": "Enervation: lack of vitality\nBellicosity: a natural disposition to fight\nPugnacity: a natural disposition to be hostile\nPacification: the act of appeasing someone or causing someone to be more favorably inclined\nAggravation: an exasperated feeling of annoyance",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/a6k2hk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ironically, the myth of Martin Van Buren`s _____ was due largely to circumstances that had little to do with Van Buren himself; in reality, of all the U.S. presidents since Andrew Jackson, Van Buren exceeded the average in education, intellect, and experience.",
    "correct_answer": "mediocrity",
    "distractor": [
      "profundity",
      "stoicism",
      "aptitude",
      "malleability"
    ],
    "support": "Mediocrity: ordinariness as a consequence of being average and not outstanding\nProfundity: wisdom that is recondite and abstruse and profound\nStoicism: an indifference to pleasure or pain\nAptitude: inherent ability\nMalleability: the property of being physically malleable; the property of something that can be worked or hammered or shaped without breaking",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/f8k2kk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "While she may have answered him truthfully-in the strictest sense of the word-it became clear to Sergei after the incident that Sheryl had actually been trying to _____ .",
    "correct_answer": "obfuscate",
    "distractor": [
      "vituperate",
      "illuminate",
      "covet",
      "desiccate"
    ],
    "support": "Obfuscate: make obscure or unclear\nVituperate: spread negative information about\nIlluminate: make lighter or brighter\nCovet: wish, long, or crave for (something, especially the property of another person\nDesiccate: lacking vitality or spirit; lifeless",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/5ck2mk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Certainly a roundabout narrative, the book-much like the others in the author`s pseudo-autobiographical series-proved to be unpopular among those who preferred _____ to loquaciousness.",
    "correct_answer": "succinctness",
    "distractor": [
      "enlargement",
      "garrulousness",
      "gregariousness",
      "perspicacity"
    ],
    "support": "Succinctness: terseness and economy in writing and speaking achieved by expressing a great deal in just a few words\nEnlargement: the act of increasing (something\nGarrulousness: the quality of being wordy and talkative\nGregariousness: the quality of being gregarious--having a dislike of being alone\nPerspicacity: intelligence manifested by being astute (as in business dealings",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/69k2nk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although they stood with the congressman in a tenuous display of solidarity, the incensed commissioners could not conceal their _____ .",
    "correct_answer": "rancor",
    "distractor": [
      "camaraderie",
      "adulation",
      "facetiousness",
      "hubris"
    ],
    "support": "Rancor: a feeling of deep and bitter anger and ill-will\nCamaraderie: the quality of affording easy familiarity and sociability\nAdulation: servile flattery; exaggerated and hypocritical praise\nFacetiousness: playful humor\nHubris: overbearing pride or presumption",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/f0k2pk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "The defense attorney`s _____ closing statement was not enough to sway the jurors in his client`s favor; stirring words could not conceal the defendant`s evident guilt.",
    "correct_answer": "eloquent",
    "distractor": [
      "deceptive",
      "lengthy",
      "crafty",
      "impromptu"
    ],
    "support": "Eloquent: expressing yourself readily, clearly, effectively\nDeceptive: causing one to believe what is not true or fail to believe what is true\nLengthy: relatively long in duration; tediously protracted\nCrafty: marked by skill in deception\nImpromptu: with little or no preparation or forethought",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/eek2tk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1770s colonial New England, Puritans _____ the celebration of Christmas, which they considered to be an odious reminder of the Pope`s tyranny.",
    "correct_answer": "repudiated",
    "distractor": [
      "placated",
      "extolled",
      "circumscribed",
      "tempered"
    ],
    "support": "Repudiated: cast off\nPlacated: cause to be more favorably inclined; gain the good will of\nExtolled: praise, glorify, or honor\nCircumscribed: subject to limits or subjected to limits\nTempered: made hard or flexible or resilient especially by heat treatment",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/cbk2vk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Many dog owners treat their pets too _____ , forgetting that canines have evolved in competitive environments in which emotional coddling was a sign of weakness.",
    "correct_answer": "indulgently",
    "distractor": [
      "aggressively",
      "quixotically",
      "fortuitously",
      "belligerently"
    ],
    "support": "Indulgently: in an indulgent manner\nAggressively: in an aggressive manner\nQuixotically: in a quixotic manner\nFortuitously: by good fortune\nBelligerently: with hostility; in a belligerent hostile manner",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/0ck2xk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Repulsed by _____ employees, the executive informed his staff that he preferred constructive criticism to calculated flattery.",
    "correct_answer": "obsequious",
    "distractor": [
      "natty",
      "profligate",
      "rapacious",
      "sententious"
    ],
    "support": "Obsequious: attempting to win favor from influential people by flattery\nNatty: marked by up-to-dateness in dress and manners\nProfligate: recklessly wasteful\nRapacious: living by preying on other animals especially by catching living prey\nSententious: abounding in or given to pompous or aphoristic moralizing",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/28k2zk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Students may consider modernist works such as James Joyce`s Finnegan's Wake to be more _____ than Victorian prose: Victorian narratives are linear and predictable, while Joyce`s tortuous plots are fragmented and fickle, and they confound the reader.",
    "correct_answer": "recondite",
    "distractor": [
      "banal",
      "elegiac",
      "mundane",
      "panegyric"
    ],
    "support": "Recondite: difficult to penetrate; incomprehensible to one of ordinary understanding or knowledge\nBanal: repeated too often; overfamiliar through overuse\nElegiac: resembling or characteristic of or appropriate to an elegy\nMundane: found in the ordinary course of events\nPanegyric: formally expressing praise",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/26k30k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ancient generals, lacking modern technologies such as radio and satellite communication, often found that one of the most significant challenges in warfare was accurate _____ of the myriad of changes on the battlefield or in the campaign.",
    "correct_answer": "appraisal",
    "distractor": [
      "fortification",
      "adulteration",
      "accretion",
      "adumbration"
    ],
    "support": "Appraisal: the classification of someone or something with respect to its worth\nFortification: defensive structure consisting of walls or mounds built around a stronghold to strengthen it\nAdulteration: being mixed with extraneous material; the product of adulterating\nAccretion: an increase by natural growth or addition\nAdumbration: the act of providing vague advance indications; representing beforehand",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/2ek32k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "In psychological literature, the \"sleeper effect\" refers to the phenomenon in which a persuasive message from a trustworthy source loses _____ over time, while the efficacy of a message from a less credible source simultaneously increases.",
    "correct_answer": "cogency",
    "distractor": [
      "prescience",
      "erudition",
      "evasiveness",
      "control"
    ],
    "support": "Cogency: persuasive relevance\nPrescience: the power to foresee the future\nErudition: profound scholarly knowledge\nEvasiveness: intentionally vague or ambiguous\nControl: exercise authoritative control or power over",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/9bk33k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pundits do not believe that the sporadic calls for her ouster-outcries spurred by both her unusual lifestyle and social policies-have compelled the monarch to seriously consider _____ .",
    "correct_answer": "abnegation",
    "distractor": [
      "vacillation",
      "castigation",
      "asceticism",
      "misanthropy"
    ],
    "support": "Abnegation: the denial and rejection of a doctrine or belief\nVacillation: indecision in speech or action\nCastigation: a severe scolding\nAsceticism: the doctrine that through renunciation of worldly pleasures it is possible to achieve a high spiritual or intellectual state\nMisanthropy: hatred of mankind",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/f9k34k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dolly Madison., the wife of President James Madison., was known especially for her _____ , remaining calm even as the British invaded Washington D.C. during the War of 1812.",
    "correct_answer": "equanimity",
    "distractor": [
      "impracticality",
      "cynicism",
      "zeal",
      "malevolence"
    ],
    "support": "Equanimity: steadiness of mind under stress\nImpracticality: concerned with theoretical possibilities rather than actual use\nCynicism: a cynical feeling of distrust\nZeal: a feeling of strong eagerness (usually in favor of a person or cause\nMalevolence: wishing evil to others",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/67k37k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Seth was extremely _____ , and did not enjoy activities that required effort to meet new people.",
    "correct_answer": "introverted",
    "distractor": [
      "extroverted",
      "gregarious",
      "lackluster",
      "jaded"
    ],
    "support": "Introverted: given to examining own sensory and perceptual experiences\nExtroverted: not introspective; examining what is outside yourself\nGregarious: (of animals\nLackluster: lacking brilliance or vitality\nJaded: exhausted",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/70k38k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some religious leaders have declared inaction on environmental issues to be _____ , because it may now be considered a sin to pollute the earth.",
    "correct_answer": "iniquitous",
    "distractor": [
      "fathomable",
      "splenetic",
      "diaphanous",
      "dilatory"
    ],
    "support": "Iniquitous: characterized by iniquity; wicked because it is believed to be a sin\nFathomable: (of depth\nSplenetic: of or relating to the spleen\nDiaphanous: so thin as to transmit light\nDilatory: wasting time",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/5ak3ak/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Because he ate high-calorie snacks while riding the exercise bike, Julie ridiculed DeRay`s workout philosophy as _____.",
    "correct_answer": "fatuous",
    "distractor": [
      "pithy",
      "indolent",
      "hackneyed",
      "precarious"
    ],
    "support": "Fatuous: extremely silly or stupid\nPithy: concise and full of meaning\nIndolent: disinclined to work or exertion\nHackneyed: repeated too often; overfamiliar through overuse\nPrecarious: affording no ease or reassurance",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/f7k3bk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "The recent convert, still a _____ with respect to the rites of her church, did not yet feel completely comfortable in her new faith.",
    "correct_answer": "tyro",
    "distractor": [
      "pilgrim",
      "iconoclast",
      "ascetic",
      "poseur"
    ],
    "support": "Tyro: someone new to a field or activity\nPilgrim: someone who journeys in foreign lands\nIconoclast: a destroyer of images used in religious worship\nAscetic: pertaining to or characteristic of an ascetic or the practice of rigorous self-discipline\nPoseur: a person who habitually pretends to be something he is not",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/43/152736649475139095/a4k3dk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Just as different people can have very different personalities, so too can pets-even those of the same species and breed possess varied _____.",
    "correct_answer": "temperaments",
    "distractor": [
      "initiations",
      "implementations",
      "aptitudes",
      "rationalizations"
    ],
    "support": "Temperaments: your usual mood\nInitiations: a formal entry into an organization or position or office\nImplementations: the act of accomplishing some aim or executing some order\nAptitudes: inherent ability\nRationalizations: the cognitive process of making something seem consistent with or based on reason",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/0/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "If one were asked who transmitted the first radio broadcast of the human voice, one might guess the _____ inventor Guglielmo Marconi, but in fact the feat was accomplished by the much less well-known Reginald Fessenden.",
    "correct_answer": "renowned",
    "distractor": [
      "infamous",
      "contingent",
      "cogent",
      "insistent"
    ],
    "support": "Renowned: widely known and esteemed\nInfamous: known widely and usually unfavorably\nContingent: possible but not certain to occur\nCogent: powerfully persuasive\nInsistent: repetitive and persistent",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/75k17k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Now known as Administrative Professionals` Day, Secretaries` Day was created in 1952 by Harry F. Klemfuss, a public relations professional who _____ the value and significance of administrative assistants in order to attract more women to the profession.",
    "correct_answer": "touted",
    "distractor": [
      "proscribed",
      "refuted",
      "undermined",
      "admonished"
    ],
    "support": "Touted: advertize in strongly positive terms\nProscribed: excluded from use or mention\nRefuted: overthrow by argument, evidence, or proof\nUndermined: destroy property or hinder normal operations\nAdmonished: advise or counsel in terms of someone's behavior",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/07k19k/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "With a similar contrast between a partly cloudy sky and a dark street, the cover of the recent rock CD _____ a famous surrealist painting from the early 1900s.",
    "correct_answer": "evokes",
    "distractor": [
      "admires",
      "obfuscates",
      "disenchants",
      "sanctions"
    ],
    "support": "Evokes: call forth (emotions, feelings, and responses\nAdmires: feel admiration for\nObfuscates: make obscure or unclear\nDisenchants: free from enchantment\nSanctions: give sanction to",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/29k1bk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although John F. Kennedy was known for his carefree flag football games, Gerald Ford should be _____ as our football president: He turned down offers to play for two National Football League teams in order to pursue a career in public service.",
    "correct_answer": "apotheosized",
    "distractor": [
      "relegated",
      "abrogated",
      "annulled",
      "criticized"
    ],
    "support": "Apotheosized: deify or glorify\nRelegated: refer to another person for decision or judgment\nAbrogated: revoke formally\nAnnulled: declare invalid\nCriticized: find fault with; express criticism of; point out real or perceived flaws",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/aak1ck/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Though many _____ endlessly praised his work, Dan often wished for some honest criticism.",
    "correct_answer": "sycophants",
    "distractor": [
      "pedants",
      "benefactors",
      "adversaries",
      "mavericks"
    ],
    "support": "Sycophants: a person who tries to please someone in order to gain a personal advantage\nPedants: a person who pays more attention to formal rules and book learning than they merit\nBenefactors: a person who helps people or institutions (especially with financial help\nAdversaries: someone who offers opposition\nMavericks: someone who exhibits great independence in thought and action",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/0ek1dk/0/0/0/0/0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sheila would often _____ about her boyfriend`s habits, but everyone could tell that her seemingly bitter complaints were mostly facetious.",
    "correct_answer": "rail",
    "distractor": [
      "waffle",
      "dissemble",
      "grieve",
      "mince"
    ],
    "support": "Rail: complain bitterly\nWaffle: pause or hold back in uncertainty or unwillingness\nDissemble: make believe with the intent to deceive\nGrieve: feel grief\nMince: make less severe or harsh",
    "url": "http://gre.kmf.com/practise/exercise/41/152736672650466929/b6k1hk/0/0/0/0/0"
  }
]
